Welcome to the next token. Today's
Monday, June 15th, 2026. I'm your host,
Dylan Mulroy, a principal software
engineer at Cloudflare, and this is a
show about three developers who do not
have the time or energy to be hosting a
podcast.
>> I'm Reese. I spent the past few years
building apps at public that people love
like on Stack Overflow and Chip Talkers.
Recently worked over at Vercel for a
year and now I'm doing a AI startup to
enable agents to [music] pull anything.
>> Hi, I'm Sunil Pai. You might know me
from my time on the React team, PartyKit
CSS-in-JS library,
or just Twitter.
Two of us work at Cloudflare who sponsor
the show, of course, and Reese just
shows up. I'm occupationally tired.
>> On today's show, we're going to be
talking about all things Fable, and
finally we'll hear Sunil calling
everyone out on their [__]
So, to get started,
I do want to talk about Fable. It is the
kind of pressing topic at the moment.
Last Thursday, I believe, Anthropic
finally released Mythos or I guess Fable
5 to the general public, and it had some
protections in it which we can dive
into. But things have changed a lot
since it was released and subsequently
banned by the US government. After the
ban occurred, I put out this tweet,
prepositioned
the the good folks of x.com, the
everything app, to consider what would
happen if all models were banned and we
had to go back to writing code by hand.
And my take on this and why I tweeted
it, I think probably all three of us
have mixed feelings on the state of our
industry and how our work has changed
with using AI models.
There's certainly part of me that
longs to go back to writing code by
hand, but there's another part of me
that is having more fun than I've ever
had developing and I think the the
responses to this tweet also kind of
reflected that. Um having gone through a
bunch of the replies, they kind of break
down into two or three categories.
Uh the first being I'd be happy,
relieved, excited to return to the way
things were uh pre-Opus 4.5. Uh a group
of people saying I'd be disappointed,
sad, upset, I'd quit my job, I'd leave
tech. Um and then there's this third
group which I find incredibly annoying
uh which were
this group of people were all that were
like
"Oh, you've only been doing this for 6
months."
Um so I'm curious like
where you guys at on Fable? Where you
guys at on like your feelings of how
your jobs have changed and uh yeah,
we'll start there.
>> I want Fable back. I
I want it back. I miss it.
Um
I don't know. It's it's interesting. I
feel like I
with with each model release,
I feel like I get to
the limits of the model over like the
course of a month
and then I'm like in my mind I can
express very clearly like how all of the
pieces need to fit together and how it
needs to do the work. Um
but then
like
I don't know. At the end of the day,
they're just like token predictors. So
if they can't predict it in the right
way, they don't uh work. But then in
terms of like
if if I feel like if the models went
away tomorrow
not much would substantially change
still in terms of like um
there's a there's a
Do you Do you remember the tweet from
Greg Brockman that was like, "How did we
write all that code before?"
>> Yeah.
>> There there was that one and I feel like
the answer to that was we just didn't
have like the ability to brute force
things the way that we do now. Uh the
reason we were able to like write so
much code before was because we had a
bunch of like really elegant patterns
and thought process put into like the
design of our software. I mean, you do
still kind of need that, but like it's
changing, I would say. Yeah, that's like
my initial kind of reads on that.
>> What about you, Sunil?
>> Yeah, I'm actually glad we get to talk
about this a week after it's done like
So, I
The first is that it's obviously dialed
for different types of tasks, right?
Like I tried using it to do like
front-end development. Like, "Hey, can
you change this? Can you change that?"
And for like 3 minutes it would start
thinking about the entire universe of
options I had of it. I'm like, "Bro,
just center the [__] div."
Um
But But then I tried it on like a bigger
PR, and it loved just going off and like
it obviously catches a bunch of edge
cases, and I really enjoyed that.
Uh but it's it's
I I suspect what's happening is at least
until maybe even like 4.7 or 4.6, these
things were trained for developer
feedback loops, but this one's clearly
like goal-seeking for like something
much longer. And because
especially in the model companies,
that's kind of how they develop software
now, right? Like they just set up a
whole bunch of context, and they just go
for it.
That being said, I definitely found it
going down like some blind alleyways. I
think that's just fundamental to the
nature of like models, like
it's still exploring latent space,
right? Like it's still exploring this
multi-dimensional space. So, the moment
it starts getting far away from
something, it starts getting like
farther farther. So, if you're not like
paying attention to the reasoning
traces, it's I think like my toes still
like suffers from that, which means
uh one of two things, I think. One is I
think it's still too expensive, but
fine, capitalism and uh
uh from what I understand uh
just institutional funds are going to
burn billions of dollars on this. Cool.
Thank you from the UK.
Um
But I think like I'm going to have to
change the way I develop like
fundamentally not like for a while I was
so happy. Yay, I I get to be this cool
principal engineer who burns tokens,
does big things. But now I'm facing the
oh, I actually need to change my
workflow and how I even like think about
the role of software.
Um
Still $250 for a day was too much for
me. I think I'm just cheap.
>> I do miss it. Don't get me wrong. It's
cool. And you also mentioned that like
you're going to have to change your
workflow. And like a big part of this is
talking about both how realistic these
workflows are for the average developer
using these tools.
And two like how that is tied into
costs. So,
unlike you guys, I actually have not
used Fable. Uh I did not get a chance
before it was taken away from us.
That being said, I perceive that I
wouldn't be the biggest fan of Fable
because it's a kind of
a very long-running
model that doesn't have supervision and
that's like antithetical to how I work
with AI right now.
That being said, given the cost of
Fable, I think Sunil, you had a really
good tweet about this uh
either of the weekend or late last week
about and I think you might have
mentioned this
about how you set off Fable on a task
and it it did it got the task done over
some amount of time, but it the price
tag on that was $250. You know, we have
tweets coming out of these model labs
talking about how they're doing all
these autonomous you know, cloud agents
uh just having being completely
hands-off, having these swarms
of sub agents or you know, having these
autonomous self-written loops.
How practical do you think these
workflows that the
the model labs are talking about and
kind of
having a degree of evangelism
with on
X or even I think you see this coming
through in the features that especially
Anthropic is adding to Claude code. Uh
they're starting to bake these into the
harness themselves. And to me
I just don't see and I have not seen
quality software produced from these
features. And to the the cost of these
features and capabilities with models
like Fable just seem
totally out of reach for most developers
and
Fortune 500s uh
adopting AI.
>> Can I pick your brain a little bit? I
just did the math and the amount I spent
$250 on that run was my monthly salary
when I started in 2006 2005 2006.
Holy [__] I mean, let's be clear third
world is already being priced out of uh
AI programming and they have to use they
have to like fundamentally have to use
open models, sovereign models, etc.
That's one thing. But you are you
actually said the thing which is none of
my software has gotten better. Like zero
uh
things that I've used. And it's fine to
say it's it's too late to say that oh
it's only the beginning. No, all the
companies of the software that I use
right now are are all using AI for code
stuff and they've had multiple software
releases. But no, I don't think I can
think of a single company who in the
last 6 months has finished 2 years of
their road map. Like that that just
doesn't make sense to me. And I'm giving
like a healthy like oh maybe they've
like 3x 4x their speed. No, it it like
doesn't show. Me I I got super happy. I
got to clear go through my backlog etc.
which is why I keep talking about like
the role of code. Like it's
>> Yeah.
>> Like it serves a different purpose right
now.
Uh I'm like working harder than ever.
It's It
This thing is too expensive, but no, I
don't I don't think the software that
comes out of OpenAI or Anthropic is
particularly sci-fi, and I'm seeing
things that I haven't seen before.
>> Yep. I I totally agree with you.
I I when I was
coming out of my existential crisis from
the holidays trying to grapple with how
our roles as software engineers are
changing, I definitely got bit by
a bit of AI psychosis where, you know,
trying to figure out how to do this
stuff, installing beads, that malware
all over my systems, and just like
trying to have swarms of orchestrated
and managed agents. And like to the
lab's credit, they have like
actual tooling built around those
workflows now, but I just don't buy
that it's producing quality. And I,
you know, maybe outside of the exception
of Anthropic's like rewrite of bun from
zig to rust, like I don't really see a
compelling
argument, at least for the day-to-day
kind of product feature development that
I think the three of us are doing.
>> I have a friend who's working at
Anthropic now, uh, who I get to send now
that I'm using the Claude desktop app, I
get to send all my feedback to.
And I'll like hit bugs using the Claude
desktop app, but they've got their like
reproduction setup going, and they've
got, um,
basically just the ability to like
fix anything that I like fix the things
that I'm able to report to them. I'd say
like decently impressed of that
iteration loop. There is like the
pushback there of like, well, there
shouldn't be bug like bugs to begin
with. Um, but then it's like, well,
we've always kind of written software
with bugs, and so
the more we're able to like close that
feedback loop of users reporting bugs to
improving the software, I think it's
interesting.
>> Do you suspect it's because it's not
just compressing bugs being fixed, but
also bugs being created? Like if you
shorten a timeline, you just end up with
the same average of like
buggy software coming out. That's not a
bad outcome. I'm just saying it's that
why it is the way it is.
>> I'd I'd be interested to see to your
like original point, Dylan, of like
going back to writing software the old
way.
Like that domain rewrite that domain
rewrite we did, I feel like
So, with the context back when Dylan and
I worked at Pexel, we spent two, three
months rewriting the systems to be in
effect. I I feel I feel like that
timeline maybe would have been able to
be shortened to about a month and a
half, I would say,
with the current tools. Would you say
that's like maybe a fair assessment?
>> I think there's parts of that project
that certainly would have been
expedited, but I still don't think
we would have came out the other side
with the quality that we had. And
there's certainly parts of it like
the the streaming API for search results
and all of the caching we did in there.
Like I there's no world where
I I at least could get a model to
produce the same quality
and
uh design
that came out of that.
>> Yeah, Hashimoto actually Hashimoto just
tweeted about this. Did you see? He just
let the LLM loose and said find perf
improvements and it found I think like
20, 30x or something. And he's like,
"Well, this sounds like a success story
except I had to tear it all down because
I knew there were 1,000x improvements,
but the LLM just couldn't find it." And
with the current setup that it made, it
would have been impossible for me to do
it. I had to like burn it down.
Do you think it's still like finding
local minima for the things that it
thinks are good?
>> I know they they miss something they
miss some ability to
reason about problems the way that
humans can in that like whenever I
approach problem-solving versus like
watching them do it, it's two completely
different chains of thoughts. I know
they they like don't understand problems
holistically and they don't understand
there's some good things that I saw and
so
so far it's been like
>> Have you read Where Good Ideas Come From
by Steven Johnson?
>> I have not.
>> So very dry book, but it's really really
good. I recommend it. He says that there
are basically six ways that ideas
happen.
Uh there are these things called fluid
networks, the adjacent possible, etc.
etc. I wrote a blog post about this and
I don't mean to be pitching my blog
here, but I did write a blog post about
it.
And like that's where my theory about
the latent space comes through. Like
when humans are thinking about ideas,
uh they'll be like, "Okay, I want to
think of like two different things and
match them." In fact, one of the things
that he talks about is the reason that
there are good ideas in cities is
because there are different kind of
people who go and sit next to each other
in a restaurant or they go out to like
meet each other and that's where the
good ideas come from. And so when you're
exploring latent space, you simply
cannot form like that connection.
Uh which is where the good idea come
from. Like do you think Fable would have
come up with
uh
the design of the architecture and I
know domains was particularly special
inside Vercel because it was a very
unique architecture. Do you think it
would have figured out even close to it
or come up with ideas for it?
Probably not, right?
>> I don't think it would have come
anywhere close
on its own to
building something given the constraints
we had that worked. I think it would
have
let us prototype our ideas faster
um and probably do like there was a lot
of benchmarking we did in measuring
memory usage and CPU usage.
Um I think it would have made
that part of the loop much better, but
like the the actual implementation
design, I just don't see it. Like the
way I work with AI today is like I
very hand-holdy. It's
guiding it
and directing architecture and talking
about types. I still do a lot of
type-driven development starting there
and working my way down.
And
the models are getting better at taking
the output of those conversations and
getting into code that I don't have to
like nitpick and refactor as much, but
they're still, at least in my
experience, really far away from like
nailing the
like the architecture and abstractions
of
uh codebases that work. I do I do want
to go back a little bit and talk about
like cost and like
is this
realistic for
the median developer even?
And
I Reese, you were saying that you your
connection at Anthropic is turning
around these bug fixes as you report
them, but again, that's somebody that
has infinite tokens inside one of the
labs.
Do you think
given the cost of these things,
you see
Y Combinator startups or Cloudflares or
your insurance companies on the Fortune
500 doing workflows like this in 6
months? And um
do you think the cost is just
too prohibitive at the moment?
>> a little bit of a capitalist on it where
I'm like, if there's like if I spend
$200 in tokens and I get $400 of output,
that's that's still like kind of a net
positive. Other thing that I think's
interesting on cost is um
Did you see the skills chat CN put out
online? It was like a slash improve
skill or something like that.
>> Yeah, yeah, I read through that.
>> I like initially dismissed it cuz I was
like, I don't know why like I I don't
really need skills, but then I was like,
oh, this is for distilling fable output
to be able to set piece and off to other
model like
like get the good reasoning tokens from
fable and then send that off to other
models to implement. My my like rough
thoughts top cost is I'm like wondering
if if if it's if it's maybe not like a
new thing in that if you think about
like startups versus incumbent
companies, like incumbent companies have
always had
more resources to like give to
engineers, like more like higher
salaries they can pay their employees. I
don't know that cost is the difference
maker when it comes to implementation.
>> Okay, let me ask you this, okay, as a YC
company.
>> I will happily take pushback on that.
>> So you you are a YC company, okay, and
you extrapolate all these desires by
these model companies what it's going to
do. What that implies is that
there is a YC company or an entire batch
of YC companies that are going to show
up with ideas, extremely detailed plans
that they feed into a code generating,
business generating machine. The only
role that the people play is finding
customers and finding bugs and desires
and features and feeding it back into
it. Would you be willing to have 1, 10,
100 Mythos runs going on concurrently
all the time? That's the role of the
business now, right? That's the thing it
does. Uh and are you willing to bet that
the revenue that you can generate, that
every single company in every single
company in the batch that YC has, that
it generates would be
so successful that it would like make up
for the thousands of dollars you're
burning in a single day?
>> Yeah, I guess I'm not thinking that you
would have like hundreds of Mythos runs
going. Like you'd use the right models
for the tasks. And so like there's
definitely scenarios where you like need
that class of model. I I feel like the
explorations around model combinations
has been really underexplored. And so
there's a lot more to be done there.
>> I agree with that, but I think the other
problem with that is something that came
out with Fable in that it will downgrade
in this case for security purposes
>> Oh, yeah, no, let's talk about that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, 100%. Okay, keep the
cost everything aside.
>> So like
>> [snorts]
>> I've never heard of an adversarial tool.
>> My my problem with this real quick is
actually not the routing to other models
because I actually do think that
is probably
something that will be important going
forward. And there was a tweet uh some
product just put out like a dynamic
router or something. Uh I saw a tweet
about that got some attention. But my
problem here is
and I could be completely wrong on this,
but my understanding is when Fable falls
back to Opus 48, that has to bust the
cache, which means you're getting
basically double charged on the
inference on whatever that entire batch
of context is. Like that seems crazy to
me given the cost of these models.
>> It's not It's not just the caching
stuff. It's also
like if you're saying I've decided that
a thing that I'm working on requires My
Tho's. And My Tho's decides, oh no, you
need like 4 date, and I'm just going to
make it stupider results for you. By the
way, I won't know unless I'm looking at
the screen, right? It's not like I get a
notification on my phone or like an
alert or something. It just does it.
So
uh yeah, that's not how I want my tools
to behave, dog. Like sorry.
Like no.
>> Yeah, I agree.
>> Just every I mean, there's also the
thing where if it detected you were
trying to talk about biology and stuff,
it decides to like sabotage you, which
is so dangerous.
And uh I'm
I'm completely against this. Uh it was
stupid It was stupid as hell. I think
they're starting to walk that stuff
back. At least call it a subagent. Like
call it a subagent. Cursor does that. It
takes a stupider model and it makes you
a subagent.
But uh not in the main thread.
>> I I think what's tough is figuring out
how you roll out models like My Tho's.
Like I do think you can at that word
that it's probably for the best that
there are cybersecurity restrictions on
it. Like I don't know that everyone in
the world having access to Mythos models
unrestricted
would be would end well.
>> Wait, do you think we should cap out
here? Like 2026 June indulgence levels
reached. That's the access to
intelligence for everyone on the planet.
>> Yeah, and so now now we just get
whatever Dario says. Like
you peons only get Opus 4A.
>> It's not so much that. It's more like if
you're going to do
um
like cybersecurity work, having like a
verification process, I don't know is
like
>> Do you think it's for the labs to decide
or do you think it's for
governments to decide and not
necessarily just the US government?
>> You're definitely going to do one of
these constitutional amendments, the
right to bear intelligence or something
like that, right?
I I I bet. Regulated YC-funded mafia now
militia or something like that. Yeah.
>> We we like have precedent for this
already on like there's like certain
intelligence you can only access once
you've like verified to access that in
that information. Like all rocket like
isn't it
like rocket development in the United
States?
>> Wait, that's information versus
intelligence. We're talking about
information or intelligence.
>> Is that the same thing? At least from
like the model's perspective, they're
the same thing.
>> Yeah.
>> Or like I'm talking about the set of
information you're trying to access.
You're like trying to access information
around cybersecurity.
>> It sounds a lot like the same arguments
that the government made about
encryption in like the late '90s. Like
>> Do you know PG What is it? P What is it?
P3P? Pretty good privacy? Yeah, the one
that they exported the like source code
of in a book.
>> Yeah, yeah. I I read something about
this this past weekend.
>> Yeah, there was a book called Pretty
Good Privacy and they
um
they did a bunch of regulations on
encryption. They like government I what
what they classified it as I think it
was thing with LMs where they classified
it as like national national security
encryption and they put export
restrictions on it and people got around
that through exploiting pretty good
privacy as a book instead because books
are freedom of speech. And so the whole
source code of it was classified as
freedom of speech written into a book.
Put this through ChatGPT cuz I was
curious if you wanted to do the same
thing for like those last models.
>> You need like a billion pages to get the
weights in.
>> Okay, but that's just like a single
flash drive, right? Like
>> Well, flash drives aren't freedom of
speech. Aren't protected under
>> This I feel like this whole thing is my
argument for why like open weight models
need to win.
And like maybe that's like un-American
of me wanting the
the Chinese labs to start catching up a
little bit more, which I think they
will.
Or Nvidia's putting out a bunch of good
open weight models, but I don't want one
or two
companies telling me what I
can or can't do or how to develop or do
my work.
>> I I think that's inevitable, by the way.
Not Not only will models get better, not
not only will hardware get better, but
people will dis- figure out how to do
distributed compute to run these
machines. People will figure out how to
chain these models separately to get
different types of intelligence. By the
way, that's another thing I've been
thinking about, which is I don't like
it. I You wouldn't hire like one type of
programmer
as your entire like workforce, like 30
of the same. I mean, that That's what
IBM used to do back in the day and they
they'd call it culture fit. Uh I suspect
intelligence comes in like different
training forms. And we will be looking
back at this conversation like we were
talking about a [__] ThinkPad from
the early 2000s or something. I think
it's inevitable at this point. Uh this
is just a uh
flash in the moment
event that we'll remember that the week
before they had a UFC fight at the White
House the intelligence model.
>> It is
sounds like fun fiction at this point.
They were riding dirt bikes off ramps, I
think. I think I saw a couple of photos.
So, it will look very quaint in the
future, I think.
>> I think the other thing is maybe like a
lead time on intelligence in that like
like I saw a a lot of people reacting on
Anthropic where they were like Anthropic
doesn't want anyone to use this for
biology ever or Anthropic doesn't want
us to use anyone to use this for
cybersecurity ever. I I possibly have
given them too much grace, but I'm sort
of thinking like I'm I'm curious to see
over the next 6 to 12 months is is it
that they are like we're going to work
on expanding access to intelligence and
this information, but we're going to try
and do it in like a responsible way or
is it going to be the opposite where
it's like this is incredibly locked
down, it's not accessible to people.
>> Let's say OpenAI releases
uh GPT-56 or six in the next week or two
or whenever.
And they don't say a single word about
it being a threat to biology, to
people's jobs, to national security.
Do you think this topic ever comes up
again and like does does it just make it
not matter then?
>> I think there's an alternate world where
xAI got a Methuselah's model first and
we see a bunch of cybersecur- I I like I
think there's an alternate timeline
we're in where xAI releases a maximally
based cyber- like maximally based
uh
model and there's no no restrictions on
it and we're like seeing we would be
like seeing some of the like biggest
data breaches we've ever seen.
>> Croc maxing.
>> What what is the US defense budget? Some
trillion? I don't know. Some absurd
>> Yeah. Uh I assume and I think Anthropic
was doing about 80 billion in revenue
this year so far or something.
Let's say they do 200 for the year.
Uh is the US government willing to uh
sole customer rights for a maximally
based model that Grok creates?
I suspect so, right? Like Elon would be
like, "Yep, you're the only customer I'm
doing." It'll be like trained on
uh optimally uh
defending the planet as it were and
bringing freedom to uh all parts of the
uh all parts of Earth.
>> All hail Grok.
>> Yeah, all hail Grok.
>> All right. We'll come back to Fable in 2
weeks' time. See how things have
progressed. See if Reese is still uh
in his anthropic psychosis. Um
and also see if GPT or OpenAI has a kind
of had their own answer to this.
>> I have to tell you, like I am tempted uh
by letting the agent do a bunch of
things while I sit back. But in
practice, I don't see that happening a
lot.
Which uh takes me to our next section,
by the way.
Uh receipts.
Uh the reason that we have a receipt
section is one of the things that
happens in the industry. I won't say
especially Twitter, but probably
especially Twitter. Uh is people love
making predictions. Oh, things are going
to change. And they start getting really
specific about it. And I think the
reason they do that is because they know
no one's checking in on them in a few
months, 2 months, 3 months, 6 months.
So, that's what we're going to do. Okay,
we are actually going to
uh we're
we have the tweets.
>> Hold people accountable.
>> Hold people accountable. If you're going
to use your reputation and your 60,000
followers
uh to
just swamp my timeline and get a bunch
of hot takes, then we're going to check
in on those predictions in a while. I
was the first uh the
for this episode, we'll take some of the
bigger popular ones, okay? Like
someone's that like everyone knows
about. So, Geoffrey Hinton, "People
should stop training radiologists now."
Uh this dude's considered the godfather
of AI, and
I feel like naming some someone
something like that means they're never
going to work on anything meaningful for
the rest of their life. It's like giving
a lifetime achievement award.
Uh but he won like the Nobel Prize in
like 2016 uh for some ML something or
the other. And his claim was, uh "People
should stop training radiologists now.
It's just completely obvious that within
5 years deep learning is going to do
better than radiologists. It might be 10
years."
>> People should stop training radiologists
now. It's just completely obvious within
5 years
um deep learning is going to do better
than radiologists cuz it's going to be
able to get a lot more experience.
>> I don't really think that's come to
pass. Are there any kinds of doctors
that have become obsolete in the last
uh 6 months to a year? What are What are
you seeing?
I I don't know what you're talking
>> I don't think so. And I think actually
the the CEO of Nvidia was on a podcast
recently.
And Jensen was talking about how, I
don't know, a decade ago, 15 years ago,
there was a bunch of murmur and talk in
the industry about how, you know,
whether it was just software engineering
in general and automation or ML was
going to replace radiologists.
And all of that discourse
actually had a negative impact, at least
in the United States, in that
people stopped pursuing
specialization or medical degrees in
radiology, and we now currently have a
shortage of radiologists in the United
States.
And I think that actually draws like a
really
uh sharp parallel to what
especially like leadership in the AI
labs are saying now, like software
engineers are going to be replaced, you
know, don't go to school for CS degrees.
Basically, things kind of
the discourse we all see happening on X.
And
it's almost
I fear doing the same thing for young
software engineers or kids in high
school trying to think about what they
want to do, like discouraging people
from going into tech.
I don't see
I don't know. I was also I'm so bad at
this predict prediction uh stuff cuz if
you would've told me
uh where where where at today a year
ago, I would've said [__]
Uh but I also at this point, even like
looking at models like Mythos and Fable
and GPT-5.5, like I don't see
the human
the technical operator of these things
going away. And at this point, I see
just like an even bigger need. I We'll
We'll talk about it in a future episode,
but what it looks like to break into the
industry and how do we level up junior
devs.
Um but I I don't I don't see
good technical operators and PMs uh
getting replaced by technology. And
especially like right now, I don't see
uh many doctors to this exact claims
point um disappearing either.
>> So, I said something on Twitter
about how I think the reason that I'm so
tired is actually because uh it's true
that these agents uh do a great job of
all the menial work and automating a
bunch of things. But it means that I
have to be like perpetually locked in
because I'm only dealing with the hard
problems.
And someone replied to that and said the
same thing is happening with doctors.
That uh because a lot of uh people who
have a slight flu or uh they get a
little rash, they go to ChatGPT for
that. It means that the only patients
they're seeing are getting uh are the
serious ailments. They can't really
Google or or get on ChatGPT.
Uh which means A, like it's getting
harder to get juniors into the industry.
Uh, but it's just putting a lot of
burden on the people who are already
here. I can I absolutely feel that.
>> Yeah, the juniors I'm letting the
industry, I think must be super tough
because
like I didn't go to like a well-known
college or anything, but like the way
that I was able to stand out on like
uh, applications is I had a bunch of
projects that I did. Like I had either
like hackathon projects or like I was
supposed to do in game development, so
like game jams, just similar thing. Like
those projects helped me stand out some.
All of those projects could be done 80
90% of the way with AI now, and that
last 10% is like very difficult, but
it's also not what people see
when they're immediately looking at an
application.
>> So it goes back to another thing we were
talking about, which is I think people
are just putting out 90% apps now all
day long anyway. I think that's why
software isn't getting really good.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Because if you're given the option to do
the last 10% versus let me do the 90% of
something else.
>> Yeah, I mean, I feel that even
I think I'm starting to pull back a
little bit. Uh, but like the beginning
of the year when this was all kind of
fresh and new, like I was just cranking
out ideas and code bases and tools left
and right, and so many of those are now
just abandoned graveyards on GitHub, and
like
not useful to anybody.
>> I think probably one of the most common
pieces of like startup advice that I see
is like just get your ideas and concepts
out into the world. And like even if
it's early, even if it's buggy, like get
something out that people can
immediately start using. And like if it
solves a problem for them, great. If
not, like
um,
figure out what the like basically you
don't know what people end up wanting,
and
you have to iterate and figure out what
that is. And it's like weird advice in
an AI world now, where that's like even
easier That's easier to do than ever.
But now so many people are doing it that
>> Yeah, I was going to say like I feel
like it's like a constant stream of
Twitter being like announcing or I just
built this or this is what I'm working
on and like I just like by default now
ignore that. Like it just I don't pay
attention to what
other than a very small handful of
people people are doing.
>> Other than these startups that sell
sleeping drugs. Like that's That's what
I want If you're selling what people are
doing
>> could probably hit up Brian Johnson.
>> Yeah, just straight up. Like
>> Brian Johnson's your guy, dude.
>> I mean I think maybe what's interesting
on it is like Dylan, you deployed the I
sent you that half-baked executor on
Cloudflare.
Uh
demo that is possibly still running on
your account.
>> It's yeah, just broken as all hell.
>> Oh, okay. I know. The new version's
good.
>> [laughter]
[gasps]
>> But there was there like there's been
enough
uh
I think it's maybe okay to put out the
90% software if you
Like I don't I don't think that you
should represent the 90% software as
like fully finished. I think like owning
it is like hey, these are like
experiments that I've done. Um this is
the problem that I'm trying to solve.
And then the other thing is if there is
that group of people that um
get enamored by it or like see the
vision, then you like keep iterating on
it to make it good. But I think I I do
feel like the only way that you can make
software and products good is like by
getting it into the hands of people to
use.
>> So, I think for this claim we're
probably all in agreement that
people should stop training as
radiologists is
a bad claim and BS and I think that can
be equally applied to uh software and
product engineering at this point.
The next The next claim that I want to
talk about here is
uh we'll group two together.
The first being Dario
who on March 10th of last year made the
claim AI will write 90% of code in 3 to
6 months and essentially all of the code
in 12 months.
>> I think I don't know. We might be 6 to
12 months away from when the model is
doing most maybe all of what squeeze do
end to end.
>> And then on top of that Sundar of Google
said more than a quarter of new code at
Google is generated by AI and he said
that in 2024, October 2024 and then
followed up on that this year saying 75%
of all new code at Google is now AI
generated.
And
I'll take the the first stab at this. I
think both of these claims, I think both
leaders and CEOs have the receipts to
back this up. In fact, I remember
tweeting there's I probably have old
tweets about Dario saying this that
there's just no world where AI would be
writing 90% of code let alone all of
code and at that point last summer in
March of last year, I was writing 95%
plus of my code.
And
as of January of this year, AI's
basically writing all but 100% of my
code.
I'm curious where you guys fall at on
this.
>> I don't like the phrase of like AI is
writing the code. The only time that I
will handwrite something now is if it's
like critically important and even then
I'm like hand writing the types in the
SDKs. Surface, I'm not handwriting the
implementation. And so like AI is like
writing that code but the like again
going back to like the last 10% like
when people when people say oh AI is
writing the code, it makes it sound too
autonomous. It's like it's giving too
much credit to Claude, I feel like.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I agree.
It's like lacking nuance.
Right? Like the nuance is like
we're still driving and steering at
least most of us.
>> I'm I'm like I'm still having to like
dictate everything and give it the
proper context and like set it up for
success. I do think that like
my role in that decreases over time.
Like I I'm not saying that that's how it
will all be for forever, but like
>> Yep.
>> AI writing 90% of the code If AI If AI
was able to write 90% of code
autonomously, I think that we'd be like
out of jobs or something like that. You
know what I mean?
>> I agree. Yeah.
>> If
>> [laughter]
>> Uh
>> There's like a distinct different Right.
We're we're kind of moving the goal post
now, but like I'd be curious I I don't
know the full video or the full quote
off the top of my head, but I'm curious
if at that time if Dario and Sundar's
thinking was that like it would be
autonomous or if in their mind it is
where we're at today where we are the
ones very much overseeing and steering
and front-loading context and research
and planning or constraints.
>> But also like I'm happy to be in that
world because like I never learned Vim
because I couldn't be bothered and now I
feel like
>> Oh my god.
>> I don't need to in that
>> That's so disappointing. It's the most
disappointing thing I've ever heard.
>> I don't need to navigate the
codebase that
you know?
>> It is fair. I have used uh them far less
this year than I have
>> That That's actually blessed in my
comment.
>> Uh well, you know, at least I learned
Vim key binds.
Uh Sundar
>> What changes have you seen in Google
software in the last 6 months?
Gmail, Google Photos, Google Search.
So there's So 75% I just checked by the
way. Google's about 190,000 employees of
which about 80 to 90,000 are engineers.
Does your software feel Just Google
software feel 2x better is the question.
Like everyone keeps making these claims
about lines of code and I'm like, but
what you know you So, for example,
uh
Cloudflare dashboard has famously, uh
how do I put this politely, uh not been
super pleasant to work with.
Uh but, you can constantly see now
people are noticing that it's like
getting better and prettier, by the way.
Like, it's actually starting to look
really nice. And all of that value is
coming because of like the people we put
on it, not because of like lines of
code.
>> Yeah.
>> So, okay, it's fine, man. Like, 90% of
code will be written by so and so. 75%
of Google.
Uh what what is the impact, bro? Like, I
just need I just need Gmail to like get
better. You know what? Like, so for the
last year, there's been a scam where you
get an email saying
uh someone logged into your X account,
please click here to like fix it. And
this seems like the most common pattern
that
um
uh
some engineer on the Gmail team should
be like, "Yep, that's spam." And that's
just not being fixed. So, I need to know
what they're writing all this code for,
bro.
Uh
I I I If you can't fix that for me, I I
I'm not super interested.
>> I will say my my Google software hasn't
gotten worse.
>> That's a low bar.
>> I It is a It is a low bar, but like I
feel like there's this weird thing
happening with AI writing code at the
moment where the software isn't getting
better, but it's also not getting The
software isn't getting exponentially
better, but it's also not getting
exponentially worse.
>> I feel like we
should be striving for the the latter.
Which This is actually a good a good uh
segue into uh
presenting new claims that don't have an
answer.
Um and I think we can probably all agree
on this past one that for the claim that
AI will be writing
X percentage of code, I think we'll put
the asterisk that they're not talking
about uh
AI autonomously
hands-off writing code. So, we've just
covered two claims that have been, you
know, hot topics in the past couple of
years, and we have come through our our
own conclusions on them. I now want to
get into the fun part of this segment,
and going forward is putting people on
the spot and
some accountability.
So, in a recent interview,
Boris
Cherny, hopefully I'm getting his name
right, of Claude Code,
created Claude Code, works at Anthropic.
He made the claim that "I don't prompt
Claude anymore. I have loops running
that prompt Claude and figuring out what
to do. My job is to write loops, and
this is a transition we're going to see
for the rest of the year."
And then on top of that, the same day,
Peter Steinberger
of OpenAI, who created Open Claude, also
tweeted out, "Here's your monthly
reminder that you shouldn't be prompting
coding agents anymore. You should be
designing loops
that prompt your agents."
And we've talked about this a little bit
already,
but this is something I'm very
interested in tracking over the next
couple months, 6 months, a year to see
how this plays out, and to see if these
guys are right, and if, you know, come
December of this year, the three of us
are now just
writing
directing agents to direct loops.
Again, we've talked about this a little
bit, but we'd love to hear where you
guys think this this ends up in 6
months.
>> Well, I think we should make our own
bets on this. Like, what's the over
under? Like,
and
let's say that he's not accurate
accurate, but like, I assume some
version of this like Peter Steinberger
and Boris Cherny are not idiots. They're
just extremely psycho susceptible.
Whatever. So, what version of this
actually comes through? That that I
would like us also to like make a
prediction on the thing. Like you can
say it's not completely it won't happen
at all, but yeah, loops sound appealing.
So, what's your bet?
>> I do feel like this is likely some form
of this is likely the future. You see
this happening with Codex with the gold
feature or
notably the pie auto research or auto
research in general popularized by
Karpathy and the guys at Spotify.
Um
I think that's effective,
but it's also very token hungry and I
don't see these workflows becoming
mainstream unless one of two things
happen. One, token at economics change
and it becomes far cheaper
to
run models and agents that can do this
kind of workflow uh with good results.
Um
Or
open models get good enough to offload
these kind of workflows to. I think
without those two things happening,
these kinds of workflows are kind of
uh
going to be gatekept by
the people that are token rich and that
can
spend tons and tons of money. Or maybe
it turns into a thing where like
maybe at Cloudflare all the principal
engineers get in a room and there's a
pool of
RFCs that we've written out. Like what
are we going to throw to you know, Fable
10 here and we bike shed that and that's
what we spend our tokens on. Um
Curious curious on your thoughts, you
know.
>> A whole bunch of VC companies will start
redefining what the word loop means.
Like they'll say, "Oh yeah, you need to
loop, but you have to involve customer
feedback in that. Therefore, we have
created a thing that collects all your
Slack complaints, tweets, etc., feeds it
back into the loop and then does another
round of like burning tokens to like fix
thing. There you go. It's the
self-healing e-commerce website where we
sell you uh surfboards uh like uh rude
surfboards. I suspect that's going to
happen anyway. Like people will but
people badly want to frame this as
something good where
it's it's the human centipede of uh
software development life cycle
software.
>> One of the ways that I like to try and
take out the noise from what's like
actually relevant is how closely things
relate to how we work today.
And loops is actually like significantly
is like very close to how we work today
in that like if you're a software
engineer, you go and you reproduce a bug
problem. Well, like you are scanning
socials, you get feedback. You go like
I'm scanning socials, I go I get
feedback, I get reproduce that feedback,
I implement a fix, I test that fix.
There's like a bunch of things. There's
one there's like what level of loop are
you in? Are you in like some inner
development loop that's like what I
demoed of being able to test test
software autonomously? Are you in more
of like a Are you in like a bigger loop
that's like you're going from customer
feedback all the way to production and
like living around that? I'm decently
bullish on a world where intelligence
continues to get better and tokens
continues and tokens get cheaper is the
world that I'm like optimizing for. I
like view it as a game of Factorio.
>> The
>> There are those good bottlenecks. There
are those like bottlenecks that exist
and what's interesting with LLMs is
they've given us the ability to remove
those bottlenecks theoretically
theoretically.
>> All right. So, con- concretely, I want
to hear from
all of us here.
>> Yeah.
>> Six months from today,
the three of us on a day-to-day basis,
how does this impact us? I'll take the
position to start that
I think that we will likely be operating
in a workflow
similar to this for for many tasks, even
probably product or feature development,
as long as the tokenomics makes sense.
Otherwise, I think you might see
a world that's more traditional to
people bikeshedding
in, you know, principal VP level rooms
and meetings on where we where we spend
the tokens at.
>> I'm going to take the position that the
tokenomics
don't use the Like, I don't consider
tokenomics as part of loops.
Uh
I view the I view tokenomics
>> Mr. Money bags over here.
>> Yeah, I I view tokenomics as like baked
into loops already. Uh
That's like, if I have to go manually
test something and report the report the
results back to the agent. Um that's
like me I'm already spending that. Not
only am I spending tokens on that, I'm
also spending my time on that.
I'm surprisingly bullish on loops. So
I think I think that they're right. I
think that loops do
yield actually decent result from LLMs.
Um at the same time, I have like
concerns on the fact that like
you lose all of the friction that you
get you you learn from friction and you
learn from
dealing with bad software how to not
write bad software.
And loops completely eliminate all of
that friction. And so you like miss the
things with that would act actually
improve or fix your code base. Uh yeah,
I'm very bullish on loops. I think that
he's pretty much correct.
>> Yeah, I think I think you're right. I
think there's a class of problems that
already obviously loop-shaped.
So in 6 months, yeah, I suspect I will
be having one or two things going on in
the background at all time.
Spending um
daddy princess money.
Uh this assumes that I haven't taken the
motorcycle into the woods to like
disappear because I'm just tired of you
all.
I was just considering doing that today
because like the weather in Newcastle is
super nice this week. I was like what if
I pretend like I lost my memory or
something? That happens in TV shows a
lot, right?
>> Grandpa Sunil has wandered off into the
woods again.
>> That's 100% what I was thinking. Like I
would make a big deal of it. I'll be
like guys, I think I need some time
like
to recover.
I would I still would like my salary and
access to tokens, though. [laughter]
>> Of course you would.
>> Yeah, of course I would still do that.
It's part of the healing process.
But no, enough problems are loop-shaped
that I suspect it's going to Yeah, it's
going to go mainstream.
>> All right. Well, I think I think that's
a wrap. Thank you everyone for joining
us on the next token episode zero. We'll
be back in 2 weeks with more opinions,
hot takes, our workflows, talking about
this and that, and whatever Sunil
happens to be dramatic about that day.
Follow the show wherever you're watching
or listening and let us know what you
think.
>> So we will be in San Francisco for AI
Engineer World Fair
which is dope. Uh Shawn Wang puts
together a I mean like everyone shows up
for this. My guys put together a
generation of conference.
So and we show up for these things. Uh
but if you're not going I think we will
actually be recording a live episode
right there at AI Engineer. That's going
to be dope. Uh but if you're not going
to see us at AI Engineer, we're actually
going to do coffee flare, which is just
coffee swag. Come and meet us. A whole
bunch of the team will be there
especially because it's a circle of a
lot of Cloudflare people.
So that's June 20th, Tuesday at a place
called Site Class Soma.
Uh
no badges, no nothing. We We might have
a sign-up thing, but you know where the
You already know where it is. You can
just show up. Uh we are famously known
for having very good caps, so [music]
you should come and get caps from us.
>> Alrighty. Thanks, y'all, and we'll see
you next time.